Louis Simpson Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Writings File, 1937-2006 (Box 47-159)
  - Miscellany (Box 98)
    - Drafts of poems with suggestions from Robert Bly, undated (Box 98)
    - Drafts of a poem written on New Years Day, undated (Box 98)
    - Early writings, 1937-1940 (Box 98)
    - Essay on Wordsworth and Proust, 1987 (Box 98)
    - Fragments, 1950, undated (Box 98)
    - James Wright biography, undated (Box 98)
    - "Literary Theory and Practice from Realism to Surrealism" introduction, 1992 (Box 98)
    - Published letters and blurbs, 1982, 1991-1993, undated (Box 98)
    - Response on the state of poetry, 1990 (Box 98)
    - Translations of Juan Ramón Jiménez (Box 98)
      - Invisible Reality introduction, 1987
      - God Desired and Desiring introduction, 1987 (Box 98)
      - Platero and I introduction, 1985 (Box 98)
      - Time and Space corrections, 1988, (3 folders) (Box 99)
      - Time and Space introduction, 1988 (Box 99)
  - Notebooks (Box 99)
    - 1962 (Box 99)
    - 1963 (Box 99)
    - circa 1970-1971, (1 folder); (6 folders) (Box 99, Box 100)
    - circa 1977 (Box 101)
    - 1983 (Box 101)
    - 1988 (Box 101)
    - circa 2006 (Box 101)
    - undated (Box 101)
  - Other People's Writings (Box 101)
    - 1960-1965, (2 folders)
    - 1966-1981, (7 folders) (Box 102)
    - 1982-1987, (7 folders) (Box 103)
    - 1988-1995, (6 folders) (Box 104)
    - 1996-2001, undated, (8 folders) (Box 105)
  - Poems, Prose, and Other Writings (Box 106)
    - "An Academic Story," circa 1990
    - "After the Exams," 1992 (Box 106)
    - "Allies," circa 1995 (Box 106)
    - "American Boys in Italy," circa 1972-1974, (2 folders) (Box 106)
    - "An American View of Pasternak," undated (Box 106)
    - "Andromeda," circa 1956 (Box 106)
    - "Another Part of the Island," 1990 (Box 106)
    - "The Arborists," 1994 (Box 106)
    - "Armidale," 1979 (Box 106)
    - "Art and Literature as Religion," undated (Box 107)
    - "The Artist," circa 1990-1995 (Box 107)
    - "The Associate," 1989, (3 folders) (Box 107)
    - "Auguries of Romance," 1990 (Box 107)
    - "The Bayman," 1991-1992, (2 folders) (Box 107)
    - "The Beaded Pear," circa 1978 (Box 107)
    - "A Bower of Roses," circa 1978 (Box 108)
    - "The Bricklayer," circa 1991 (Box 108)
    - "Bricks," 1991 (Box 108)
    - "The Cabin," 1990 (Box 108)
    - "A Castle in Spain," circa 1953 (Box 108)
    - "A Change of Raiment," 1991 (Box 108)
    - "The Character of the Poet," 1984-1985, (3 folders) (Box 108)
    - "The Characters Set Free," circa 1990 (Box 108)
    - "Cicadas," 1990 (Box 109)
    - "Clippings," undated (Box 109)
    - "Country Music," 1990 (Box 109)
    - "The Day Dreamer," undated (Box 109)
    - "A Deadly Welcome," 1995 (Box 109)
    - "Disorder and Escape in the Fiction of V. S. Naipal," circa 1987, (3 folders) (Box 109)
    - "An Explosive Moment," 1989 (Box 109)
    - "Facts and Poetry," circa 1988 (Box 109)
    - "Fairy Gold," circa 1991 (Box 109)
    - "The Father Out of the Machine," undated (Box 109)
    - "Foggy Lane," 1970 (Box 109)
    - "French Provincial," 1991, (2 folders) (Box 110)
    - "From Realism to Surrealism: Art and Anti-Art," undated (Box 110)
    - "The Further Off From England," circa 1996 (Box 110)
    - "God Placed Between the Cells," circa 1995 (Box 110)
    - "Great Books and Good Grades: Memoirs of an English Professor," circa 1995 (Box 110)
    - "Honeymoon," 1990 (Box 110)
    - "The House of the Stare," 1990 (Box 110)
    - "How Caliban Saw It," 1991 (Box 110)
    - "Humane Letters," 1990 (Box 110)
    - "Inhumane Letters," 1993 (Box 110)
    - "The Invasion of Italy," 1976 (Box 111)
    - "Irish Ghosts," 1988, 1993 (Box 111)
    - "An Irish Poet," circa 1978 (Box 111)
    - "Islanders," 1977 (Box 111)
    - "Jabez," 1988 (Box 111)
    - "Jimmy," 1992 (Box 111)
    - "Judith," undated (Box 111)
    - "A Leave of Absence," circa 1990 (Box 111)
    - "Lindstrom and the Dwarf," 1990 (Box 111)
    - "Literature and Belief," circa 1995, (2 folders) (Box 111)
    - "Little Aunt," undated (Box 111)
    - "The Lonely Pool," circa 1955 (Box 111)
    - "Lovely Life Bird Livelily Sing," undated (Box 111)
    - "Lucia," 1981-1982, (2 folders) (Box 112)
    - "The Magic Carpet," 1987 (Box 112)
    - "Making it New: An Essay on Modernism," undated, (4 folders) (Box 112)
    - "The Making of Modern Poetry," undated (Box 113)
    - "The Man Freed from the Order of Time," 1987 (Box 113)
    - "The Man Who Sold Ice Boxes," circa 1955 (Box 113)
    - "Maria Roberts," circa 1979 (Box 113)
    - "Maxwell Dane," undated (Box 113)
    - "The Memorial and the Garden," 1991, (2 folders) (Box 113)
    - "Milparinka," undated (Box 113)
    - "Modernism: An Essay," 1994 (Box 113)
    - "Modernism and its Origins," 1990, (2 folders) (Box 114)
    - "Moody Colonials," circa 1991 (Box 114)
    - "Most Accidents Happen in the Home," 1998 (Box 114)
    - "The Mouth of Fame," 1993 (Box 114)
    - "Moving Right Along," undated (Box 114)
    - "My Beginnings," 1987, (3 folders) (Box 114)
    - "The Mysterious Strangers," undated, (2 folders) (Box 115)
    - "New Tenants," undated (Box 115)
    - "A Not Entirely White Christmas," 1992 (Box 115)
    - "Notes of the Old Boy's Association," circa 1990, (2 folders) (Box 115)
    - "An Old Woman's Story," 1997 (Box 115)
    - "On Teaching," 1957, 1967, 1974, 1992 (Box 115)
    - "On the Neglect of Poetry in the United States," 1991, (2 folders) (Box 115)
    - "The Other Jamaican," 1987, (3 folders) (Box 116)
    - "Out of Season," circa 1979, (2 folders) (Box 116)
    - "The Pawnshop," circa 1978 (Box 116)
    - "Paths of Glory," undated (Box 116)
    - "Perkalov and the Prince of Zamask," 1950 (Box 116)
    - "Personals," circa 1985 (Box 116)
    - "Phenomena of Constant Surprise," circa 1995 (Box 116)
    - "Physical Universe," circa 1982 (Box 116)
    - "The Pink Alligator," circa 1955 (Box 116)
    - "Planes in Relation: Ezra Pound and Futurism," 1986 (Box 117)
    - "Poetry and Word Processing: One or the Other, not Both," 1988 (Box 117)
    - "Poetry Comes Down to Earth," 1987 (Box 117)
    - "Poetry in the United States," 1972 (Box 117)
    - "Poets and the Public," 1996 (Box 117)
    - "The Poet's Theme," 1988, (3 folders) (Box 117)
    - "Poor Girl's Faust," undated (Box 117)
    - "A Portrait of the Author as the Professor," 1992 (Box 117)
    - "Postmodernism: An Afterthought," undated (Box 117)
    - "The Precinct Station," 1985-1987 (Box 118)
    - "The Previous Tenant," 1982 (Box 118)
    - "The Professor," 1988 (Box 118)
    - "Property and Other Values," 1990 (Box 118)
    - "A River Running By," circa 1979 (Box 118)
    - "Romantics and Symbolists," undated (Box 118)
    - "The Salmon Fishers," circa 1995, (2 folders) (Box 118)
    - "The Saying," 1989-1990 (Box 118)
    - "Schliomy Goes to the Post Office," 1991 (Box 118)
    - "Searching for the Ox," circa 1975 (Box 119)
    - "Seashells," 1992 (Box 119)
    - "Simplicity," circa 1968 (Box 119)
    - "Social Comforts," undated (Box 119)
    - "Society Notes," 1990 (Box 119)
    - "Soldier's Heart," circa 1998 (Box 119)
    - "Some People," circa 1991 (Box 119)
    - "The Springs at Gadara," 1975 (Box 119)
    - "Strategies of Sex in Whitman's Poetry," 1988-1993, (2 folders) (Box 119)
    - "Straying," circa 1969 (Box 119)
    - "The Stuff of Life," 1991 (Box 119)
    - "Swimming Tanks and Floating Helmets," 1989 (Box 119)
    - "Thoughts About a Doubtful Enterprise," 1990-1991 (Box 120)
    - "Three Chimneys," 1989-1990 (Box 120)
    - "Treetops," 1994 (Box 120)
    - "Trouble," 1987 (Box 120)
    - "Unfinished Life," circa 1979 (Box 120)
    - "The Vertical and Horizontal of Love," 1998 (Box 120)
    - "The Vigil," circa 1992, (3 folders) (Box 120)
    - "Villa Selene," 1988, (3 folders) (Box 121)
    - "Voices in the Plaza: Berkeley in the Sixties," 1988 (Box 121)
    - "A Walk with Bashō," 1990 (Box 121)
    - "War and Peace," 1989 (Box 121)
    - "Waterloo, the Story of an Obsession," 1993 (Box 121)
    - "Wei Wei," 1990 (Box 121)
    - "Why Do You Write About Russia," 1979 (Box 121)
    - "Why I Don't I Use a Word Processor," 1987 (Box 121)
    - "The Wife of Theseus," undated (Box 121)
    - "A Wooden Bowl," 1990-1991 (Box 121)
  - Reviews by Simpson, 1967-1994, (4 folders) (Box 122)
  - Reviews of Simpson (Box 122)
    - The Arrivistes, 1949-1950
    - At the End of the Open Road, 1963-1964 (Box 122)
    - The Best Hour of the Night and People Live Here, 1983-1986, (2 folders) (Box 122)
    - Caviare at the Funeral, 1980-1981 (Box 122)
    - Collected Poems, 1988-1990 (Box 123)
    - A Company of Poets, 1981, 1985 (Box 123)
    - A Dream of Governors, 1959-1960 (Box 123)
    - In the Room We Share, 1990-1991 (Box 123)
    - James Hogg: A Critical Study, 1963-1964 (Box 123)
    - The King My Father's Wreck, 1994-1995 (Box 123)
    - Miscellany, 1971-1996 (Box 123)
    - New Poets of England and America, 1957-1958 (Box 123)
    - North of Jamaica, 1973 (Box 123)
    - The Owner of the House, 2003 (Box 123)
    - Poets of Today II, 1955-1956 (Box 123)
    - A Revolution in Taste, 1978-1980 (Box 123)
    - Riverside Drive, 1962 (Box 123)
    - Searching for the Ox, 1976-1979 (Box 123)
    - Selected Poems, 1965-1966 (Box 124)
    - Selected Prose, 1989-1990 (Box 124)
    - Ships Going Into the Blue, 1995-1996 (Box 124)
    - There You Are, 1995-1997 (Box 124)
    - Three On The Tower: The Lives And Works of Ezra Pound, T. S. Eliot and William Carlos Williams, 1975-1979 (Box 124)
  - Translations by Simpson (Box 124)
    - Blok, Alexander, 1992
    - Desbordes-Valmore, Marceline, 1995 (Box 124)
    - Jaccottet, Phillipe, 2001 (Box 124)
    - Miscellany, undated (Box 124)
    - Voznesensky, Andrei, 1967 (Box 124)
  - Translations of Simpson (Box 124)
    - Berghash, Rachel, 1983
    - Claeson, Stewe, 1990, 1998 (Box 124)
    - D'Alessandro, Nicolò, 1989 (Box 124)
    - de Nicolás, Antonio, 1995 (Box 124)
    - Fauchereau, Serge, 1989 (Box 125)
    - Miscellany, 1963, 1966, 1973, 1992, undated (Box 125)
  - Undergraduate and graduate course work, circa 1947-1959, (3 folders) (Box 125)
  - Unpublished novels (Box 125)
    - "Bed Full of Monkeys"
      - Working drafts, circa 1980, (2 folders); (6 folders) (Box 126)
      - Discarded pages, circa 1980 (Box 127)
      - Final draft, 1980 (Box 127)
    - "Black and Gold," 1946, (3 folders) (Box 127)
    - "Donovan Vanishes," undated, (2 folders) (Box 128)
    - "Life and Poetry" (Box 128)
      - Working drafts, circa 1968, (3 folders)
      - First draft, circa 1968, (4 folders) (Box 129)
      - Second draft, circa 1968, (2 folders) (Box 129, Box 130)
      - Revised draft, circa 1968, (4 folders) (Box 130)
    - "The Mirror for Murder," 1943, (3 folders) (Box 131)
    - "Touch-and-Go" (Box 131)
      - Working drafts, 1950, (4 folders)
      - Final draft, 1950, (2 folders) (Box 132)
    - "Where Early Falls the Dawn," 1952, (2 folders) (Box 132)
  - Working drafts (Box 132)
    - circa 1950-1960, (2 folders)
    - circa 1960-1970, (6 folders) (Box 133, Box 134, Box 135, Box 136, Box 137, Box 138, Box 139, Box 140)
    - circa 1970-1980, (6 folders); (5 folders) (Box 141, Box 142, Box 143, Box 144, Box 145)
    - circa 1980-1988, (6 folders) (Box 146, Box 147, Box 148, Box 149, Box 150, Box 151, Box 152)
    - circa 1989-2000, (6 folders); (7 folders) (Box 153, Box 154, Box 155, Box 156, Box 157, Box 158, Box 159)
- Professional File, 1940-2006 (Box 160-188)
  Materials spanning Louis Simpson's career as a writer and professor. Includes correspondence and related material with publishers and publications, professional organizations, judging panels, speaking engagements, poetry readings, and copyright permissions. Also includes memoranda and administrative files produced during Simpson's tenure at the University of California, Berkeley and State University of New York at Stony Brook.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Academic appointments, circa 1954-1980 (Box 160)
  - Academy of American Poets, 1956-1985, 1996, 1998, (3 folders) (Box 160)
  - Adventures of the Letter I, 1970 (Box 160)
  - American Poetry Review, 1972-1986, 1994-1999, (2 folders) (Box 160)
  - American Scholar, 1956-1972, 1979-1995 (Box 160)
  - Apple Tree Alley, 1995 (Box 161)
  - The Arrivistes, circa 1950 (Box 161)
  - Athenum Publishers, 1959-1978, (2 folders) (Box 161)
  - Bloodaxe Books, 1992-1993 (Box 161)
  - BOA Editions Ltd., 1973-1996, 2001-2003, (3 folders) (Box 161)
  - Briarwood Writer's Alliance, 1987-1990 (Box 161)
  - Bucknell University, 1991, (2 folders) (Box 162)
  - Columbia University, 1940-1965, (2 folders) (Box 162)
  - The Character of the Poet, 1984-1987 (Box 162)
  - Collected Poems, 1987-1997, (2 folders) (Box 162)
  - Columbia University Forum See Container 18, Wensberg, Erik (Box 162)
  - A Company of Poets, 1980 (Box 162)
  - Contemporary American Poetry (Macedonian translation), 1971 (Box 163)
  - Contemporary American Poetry, Second Edition (Macedonian translation), 1996 (Box 163)
  - Contracts, 1960-1988, 1996, (2 folders) (Box 163)
  - Engagements (Box 163)
    - 1960-1973, (5 folders)
    - 1974-1983, (7 folders) (Box 164)
    - 1984-1987, (8 folders) (Box 165)
    - 1988-1991, (9 folders) (Box 166)
    - 1992-1996, (8 folders) (Box 167)
    - 1997-2004, undated See also Oversize, (5 folders) (Box 168)
  - Franklin Watts, Inc., 1979-1985 (Box 168)
  - General publishing correspondence (Box 168)
    - 1971-1972, 1978-1981, (4 folders)
    - 1982-1994, (7 folders) (Box 169)
    - 1995-2002, (8 folders) (Box 170)
    - 2003-2005, (2 folders) (Box 171)
  - Gettysburg Review See Container 17, Stitt, Petter (Box 171)
  - Guggenheim Foundation, 1958-1999 (Box 171)
  - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1956, 1965-1973, 1983-1987 (Box 171)
  - Harper and Row, Publishers, 1965-1987 (Box 171)
  - Harper's Magazine, 1950, 1964-1967, 1980, 2002 (Box 171)
  - Hudson Review, 1955-1964, 1973, 1980-2005, (2 folders); (5 folders) (Box 171, Box 172)
  - In the Room We Share, 1988-1990
  - Introduction to Poetry, Second Edition, 1971-1972
  - Introduction to Poetry, Third Edition, 1984-1986, (2 folders) (Box 173)
  - Invitations, 1980-1993 (Box 173)
  - Juries (Box 173)
    - Bollingen award, 1975-1976
    - Brandeis University Creative Arts Awards, 1959 (Box 173)
    - Hopwood Poetry Contest, 1962, 1975 (Box 173)
    - Miscellany, 1960-1965, 1987-1988 (Box 173)
    - National Book Award, 1956, 1993-1994, (3 folders) (Box 173)
    - New York Foundation for the Arts, 1995 (Box 174)
    - Poet's Prize, 1993-2006, (3 folders) (Box 174)
    - Walt Whitman Award, 1974-1979 (Box 174)
  - The King My Father's Wreck, 1991-1995, (2 folders) (Box 174)
  - The Listener, 1971-1985 (Box 175)
  - MacMillan Publishing Co., 1977-1979 See also Container 11, Levine, Robert (Box 175)
  - Modern Poets of France, 1995-1998, (2 folders) (Box 175)
  - New Criterion, 1979, 1986-2005, (2 folders) (Box 175)
  - New York Times, 1964-1968, 1975-1997, 2003 (Box 175)
  - New Yorker, 1952-1982, 1991-2004, undated, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 175, Box 176)
  - Ohio Review, 1972-2000, (2 folders) (Box 176)
  - Oliver and Boyd, Ltd., 1960-1970 (Box 176)
  - The Owner of the House, 2001-2004 (Box 176)
  - Oxford University Press, 1965-1985, 1993-2002 (Box 176)
  - Paragon House, 1984-1994 (Box 176)
  - People and Trees, 1994-1996 (Box 176)
  - People Live Here, 1982-1989, (2 folders) (Box 177)
  - Permissions (Box 177)
    - Anthologies featuring Louis Simpson, 1980-1999, (4 folders)
    - The Best Hour of the Night, 1981-1985, (2 folders) (Box 178)
    - The Character of the Poet, 1985 (Box 178)
    - A Company of Poets, 1980 (Box 178)
    - In the Room We Share, 1989 (Box 178)
    - Introduction to Poetry, 1984-1986 (Box 178)
    - The King My Father's Wreck, 1993-1994 (Box 178)
    - "Louis Simpson and the Face of the Unknown," 1989 (Box 178)
    - Miscellany, 1955-2002, 2008, (7 folders); (2 folders) (Box 179, Box 180)
    - Poems set to music, 1993-1999 (Box 180)
    - Recordings, 1959, 1980-1990 (Box 180)
    - A Revolution in Taste, 1977-1979 (Box 180)
    - Searching for the Ox, 1975, (2 folders) (Box 180)
    - Ships Going Into the Blue, 1990-1994 (Box 180)
    - Television, 1990-1997 (Box 181)
    - Three On The Tower: The Lives And Works of Ezra Pound, T. S. Eliot and William Carlos Williams, 1974 (Box 181)
  - Poetry Center, 1960-1985 (Box 181)
  - Poets and Writers, 1971-1985 (Box 181)
  - Poets of Today II: Good News of Death and Other Poems, 1955 (Box 181)
  - Poet's Prize, 1989-1999 (Box 181)
  - Publication history, undated (Box 181)
  - Publicity, 1986-2003, (2 folders) (Box 181)
  - Pulitzer Prize (Box 182)
    - Congratulations, 1964, (4 folders)
    - Jury, 1966-1979, 1985-1986, (4 folders); (8 folders) (Box 182, Box 183)
    - Miscellany, circa 1983 (Box 183)
    - News clippings, 1964 (Box 183)
    - Open letter, 1990 (Box 183)
  - Requests for poems and articles, 1974-1995, (3 folders) (Box 184)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1964-1967, 1980-1986, undated (Box 184)
  - Roth Publishing, Inc., 1986-1988 (Box 184)
  - Selected Prose, 1987-1988, (2 folders) (Box 184)
  - Ships Going Into the Blue, 1993-1994 (Box 184)
  - Southern Review, 1963-1976, 1987-2004, (2 folders) (Box 185)
  - St. Martin's Press, 1959-1975, 1984-1991 (Box 185)
  - State Universities of New York, 1975-1994 (Box 185)
  - State University of New York at Stony Brook (Box 185)
    - Addendum to faculty personnel forms, 1989-1992
    - Awards, 1967, 1973, 1988-1992 (Box 185)
    - Chronological file, 1967-1996, (2 folders); (6 folders) (Box 185, Box 186)
    - Graduate courses, 1989-1996 (Box 186)
    - Honorary degrees committee, 1983 (Box 186)
    - Payroll, 1990-1993 (Box 186)
    - Poetry Center, 1978-1983, 1993-1994, (2 folders) (Box 187)
    - Reading list, 1969, 1975, 1983 (Box 187)
    - Reserve books, 1990-1991 (Box 187)
    - Undergraduate courses, 1992 (Box 187)
  - Story Line Press, 1987-2003, (2 folders) (Box 187)
  - There You Are, 1994-1996, (2 folders) (Box 187)
  - University of California, Berkeley, 1959-1967, (2 folders) (Box 188)
  - Visiting professorships, 1976-1985 (Box 188)
  - Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.), 1960-1966, 1977-1981 (Box 188)
  - Wesleyan University Press, 1958-1997, (3 folders) (Box 188)
  - William Morrow and Co., 1973-1983 See also Container 11, Levine, Robert (Box 188)
- Subject File, 1922-2011 (Box 189-212)
  Collected material, personal papers, scrap books, memorabilia, and various files originating from Louis Simpson's personal filing cabinets.
  - Articles about Simpson, 1958-1998, (3 folders) (Box 189)
  - Awards and honors (Box 189)
    - Academic degrees (Columbia University), 1950-1959 (Box 189)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters Award for Poetry, 1976 (Box 189)
    - Columbia University Medal for Excellence, 1965 (Box 189)
    - Elmer Holmes Bobst Award in Arts and Letters, 1987 (Box 189)
    - Harold Morton London Translation Award, 1998-1999 (Box 189)
    - Honorary degree (Adelphi University), 1997 (Box 189)
    - Honorary degree (Eastern Michigan University), 1977 (Box 190)
    - Miscellany, 1957, 1965, 1980, 1990, 1999 (Box 190)
    - New York State Conspicuous Cross, 1993 (Box 190)
    - White House Salute to Poetry and American Poets, 1980 (Box 190)
  - Biographies, circa 1986, 1994-1995 (Box 190)
  - Birth certificate, 1946, 1973 (Box 190)
  - Bly, Robert, 1960-1961 (Box 190)
  - Book jackets, circa 1970-1995 (Box 190)
  - Book prices, 1984, 1993-1994 (Box 190)
  - Book sales, 1984-1986, 1994 (Box 190)
  - Books on consignment in bookstores, 1983-1985 (Box 190)
  - Caroline Church, 2000-2005 (Box 190)
  - Collected articles and prose, 1979-2004, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 190, Box 191)
  - Collected poems, 1977-1982 (Box 191)
  - Critics' quotes, undated (Box 191)
  - Engler, Arlene, 2003-2005 (Box 191)
  - Family (Box 191)
    - de Marantz, Rosalind, circa 1937-1990, (3 folders)
    - Fletcher, Douglas, 1991 (Box 191)
    - Fletcher, Sybil, circa 1980-1986 (Box 191)
    - Marantz family, 1948, undated (Box 192)
    - Simpson, Anne, circa 1965-1972 (Box 192)
    - Simpson, Anthony, circa 1966-1990, (6 folders) (Box 192)
    - Simpson, Aston, circa 1939-1954 (Box 193)
    - Simpson, Herbert, 1965-1968, circa 1980-1985 (Box 193)
    - Simpson, Keith, 1988-1993 (Box 193)
    - Simpson, Matthew, circa 1960-1982, (2 folders) (Box 193)
  - Fauchereau, Serge, circa 1973-1977 See also Container 6, Fauchereau, Serge (Box 193)
  - Finances, circa 1960-2008, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 193, Box 194)
  - Fishing, 1980, 1996 (Box 194)
  - Futurism, 1986 (Box 194)
  - Hall, Donald, circa 1958-1993, (2 folders) (Box 194)
  - Hate mail, 1975-1991 (Box 194)
  - Home maintenance, 1993, 2001-2002 (Box 195)
  - Interviews of Simpson, 1965-1967, 1973-2002, (5 folders) (Box 195)
  - Jamaica (Box 195)
    - Miscellany, circa 1992-1994 (Box 195)
    - Munro College, 1937-1942 (Box 195)
    - The Munronian, 1967-1968, 1984-1990 (Box 196)
    - National Library, 1986-1987 (Box 196)
    - Phillip Sherlock lecture, 1994 (Box 196)
    - Teaching, 1991-1992 (Box 196)
    - World Class Gala, 1996 (Box 196)
  - Lenz, Frederick, 1978-1991 (Box 196)
  - MacDiarmid, Hugh (Box 196)
    - Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 196)
    - Correspondence with Helen Cruickshank, 1922-1962, (2 folders) (Box 197)
    - Interview, 1963 (Box 197)
    - Miscellany, 1932, circa 1963 (Box 197)
    - News clippings, circa 1943-1962 (Box 197)
    - Writings, 1952-1962, (2 folders) (Box 197)
    - Writings about, circa 1930-1956 (Box 197)
  - Magazine addresses, 1987-1992 (Box 198)
  - Marriage documents, 1949-1959, 1978-1979, 1985 (Box 198)
  - McDowell, Robert, 1989, 1996 (Box 198)
  - Medical documentation, 1946-1952, 1966-1967 (Box 198)
  - Miscellany, undated, (3 folders) (Box 198)
  - Model trains, 1993-1994 (Box 198)
  - Modernism, undated (Box 198)
  - MX Bookfinder, 1998 (Box 198)
  - National Poetry Foundation, 1996 (Box 199)
  - News clippings, circa 1960-2002 (Box 199)
  - Notes, undated (Box 199)
  - Off The Page, 1990-1991 (Box 199)
  - On Louis Simpson: Depths Beyond Happiness, 1987-1989, (2 folders) (Box 199)
  - Paris, France, 1982-1986 (Box 199)
  - Passports, circa 1945-1995 (Box 199)
  - Pen International, 1987 (Box 199)
  - Personal miscellany, 1942-1967, 1997 (Box 200)
  - Photographs and drawings, circa 1940-1990 (Box 200)
  - Poetry Group, 2001-2011, (4 folders) (Box 200)
  - Poet's House, 1987-1990 (Box 200)
  - Poet's master class, 2000-2001 (Box 200)
  - Police reports, 1995-1997 (Box 200)
  - Port Jefferson, N.Y., 1977, 1991 (Box 201)
  - Post-modernism, 1988,1994 (Box 201)
  - Princeton Club, 1983 (Box 201)
  - Property sale, 1978-1979 (Box 201)
  - Realism, 1981-1982 (Box 201)
  - Recommendations, 1971-2002, (4 folders); (5 folders) (Box 201, Box 202)
  - Remittance, 1954-1955 (Box 202)
  - Resnick, Donald, circa 1983-2000 See also Container 13, Resnick, Donald, (2 folders) (Box 203)
  - Scrapbooks (Box 203)
    - 1949
    - 1953 (Box 203)
    - 1957 (Box 204)
    - 1963 (Box 204)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 205)
    - 1966-1968 (Box 205)
    - 1969-1973 (Box 205)
    - 1973 (Box 206)
    - 1980-1982
  - Small press, 1978-1990 (Box 206)
  - Souvenirs, circa 1940-1970, (2 folders) (Box 206)
  - Spanish, undated (Box 206)
  - St. James Episcopal Church, 2002-2003 (Box 206)
  - Stevens, Wallace, undated, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 206, Box 207)
  - Stony Brook School, 1998-2006 (Box 207)
  - Structuralism, 1981, 1991 (Box 207)
  - Surrealism, undated, (3 folders) (Box 207)
  - Symbolism, undated, (3 folders) (Box 208)
  - Teaching notes and handouts, undated (Box 208)
  - Thank you letters, 1970-1996, (2 folders); (1 folders) (Box 208, Box 209)
  - Therapy, 1974-1978, 1997 (Box 209)
  - Thompson, Ralph, circa 1992-2000 See also Container 17, Thompson, Ralph, (3 folders) (Box 209)
  - Travel (Box 209)